Guide to the James Hershberg poster collection, 1980-1990 MS2203.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
James Hershberg poster collection
1980-1990
1989-1990
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Hershberg, James G.
MS2203.UA
13.25 Linear Feet 3 flat boxes, 41 map folders
This collection contains posters documenting the changing social and political culture in the former Soviet Union and Europe (particularly Eastern Europe) during the collapse of Communism in Eastern Europe and the breakup of the Soviet Union.
Biographical / Historical
Professor James Hershberg (1960- ) is Associate Professor of History and International Affairs in the Elliott School of International Affairs at George Washington University. Hershberg was born in New York City, and received an A.B. in American History from Harvard College in 1982; a Master of International Affairs from Columbia University in 1985; and a Ph.D. from Tufts University in 1989.
Hershberg came to GWU in 1997. He serves as editor of the Cold War International History Project books series co-published by the Stanford University and Wilson Center presses. He received the 1994 Stuart Bernath Prize from the Society for Historians of American Foreign Policy. Hershberg specializes in international history of the Cold War, contemporary international relations, and nuclear history.
Scope and Contents note
This collection contains posters with dates ranging from 1980-1990. The posters, collected by Professor James Hershberg, document the changing social and political culture in the former Soviet Union and Europe (particularly Eastern Europe) during the collapse of Communism in Eastern Europe and the breakup of the Soviet Union. A significant portion of the posters in this collection were used in a 1999 exhibit at Gelman Library titled "Goodbye Comrade: An Exhibition of Images from the Revolution of '89 and the Collapse of Communism."
This collection was donated by Professor James Hershberg in 1999.
Arrangement
Posters are arranged alphabetically by title. Whenever possible, titles used in the 1999 exhibit "Goodbye Comrade: An Exhibition of Images from the Revolution of '89 and the Collapse of Communism" have been retained.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James G. Hershberg, 1999.
Posters -- 20th century; Communism -- Soviet Union; Communism -- Europe, Eastern; Political posters; Hershberg, James G.
- 18 Months, 1988 (Map-folder 1)
  Language of Material
  Slovenia
- 20 May - Now or Never: Down with Communism!, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 21 August - Day of Russian Freedom, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 45 Years is Enough!, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 301, 1989 (Map-folder 2)
- A Correct Understanding of the Past Means a More Secure Path to the Future, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- A Minor Apocalypse, 1990 (Map-folder 3)
- Against Pig-Headedness and Corruption, undated (Map-folder 4)
- Armenian National Movement, 1989 (Map-folder 5)
- Armenian National Movement, 1989 (Map-folder 6)
- Baltic States Calendar, 1989 (Map-folder 7)
- Barbed Wire Microphone, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Berlin, 9 November 1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Century of Pasternak, 1990 (Map-folder 8)
- Chinese Communism, undated (Map-folder 9)
- Citizens for Citizens, undated (Map-folder 10)
- "...Climb Down and Get to Work!", undated (Map-folder 11)
- Congress of People's Deputies, 1988 (Map-folder 12)
- Croatian Democratic Union, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Croatian Democratic Union, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Dialogue?, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Don't Whistle, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Durchbruch '90, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Entire Power to the Soviets!, 1989 (Map-folder 13)
- European Liberals/National Liberal Party, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- First Congress of the Socialist Party of Serbia United Congress, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- For I Love Serbia, 1989 (Map-folder 14)
- For Movement - For Lithuania, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- For Them We Already "Voted", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- The Free Choice, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Free. Romania, December 1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Glasnost and the Ecology, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Goodbye, Comrade..., undated (Map-folder 15)
- Goodbye, Comrade..., undated (Map-folder 16)
- Gorbachev, Mikhail Sergeevich, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Great Socialist October Revolution, undated (Map-folder 17)
- Hammer and Sickle Cartoon, undated (Map-folder 18)
- Hold Together!, 1989 (Map-folder 19)
- Hurray! Gorbachev Falls on His Nose!, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- I Praise My Leipzig. Dedicated to the Demonstrators of the City, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- I Will Build a New Day Myself, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- If Your Program Agrees with Our Orders We Support You, Candidate, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Instructions for Managing Field Work, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Ion Iliescu - We Trust Him, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- It Must Not Happen Again! (1 of 3), undated (Map-folder 20)
- It Must Not Happen Again! (2 of 3), undated (Map-folder 21)
- It Must Not Happen Again! (3 of 3), undated (Map-folder 22)
- The "King" Is Naked!, 1989 (Map-folder 23)
- Nagy Imre: He Said..., 1989 (Map-folder 24)
- Nature's Revenge, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Neither Party, Nor State, Nor Police Can Destroy Fotogrupa M, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Not Right. Not Left. Straight to Europe!, 1990 (Map-folder 25)
- "...Or Else the Night Takes You", 1989 (Map-folder 26)
- Our Candidate, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Perestroika, 1989 (Map-folder 27)
- Politburo of the Central Committee of the Communist Party Soviet Union, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Preserve Vegetation!, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Rock '89, 1989 (Map-folder 28)
- Scientists for the Village, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Service to the Soviet Union, 1988 (Map-folder 29)
- Slovakia: Public Against Violence, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Sober People - Free People, 1989 (Map-folder 30)
- "Socialism" - Where There Is Much Light There Is Much Shadow, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Solidarity Has Not Given In, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Soon I Will, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- SOS, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Souvenir: What Is Left, 1989 (Map-folder 31)
- Stalinism, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
- State of Fear, undated (Map-folder 32)
- Stop!, 1986 (Map-folder 33)
- SVOBODU, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
- The Time Belongs to Us, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- The Time Belongs to Us, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Tiananmen Square, 1989 (Map-folder 34)
- Time to Gather Stones, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
- To Each His Own Estonia?, undated (Map-folder 35)
- Unbreakable Union of the Free Republics, 1987 (Map-folder 36)
- Vaclav Havel, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- VELVET REVOLUTION PRAGUE: It's Already Here, undated (Map-folder 37)
- Vote for SOLIDARNOSC - Lech Walesa - Elections '89, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Vote With Us, undated (Map-folder 38)
- Voters, Let's Be Vigilant, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- We Build Walls Also Against the East, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- We Want Number Seven, undated (Map-folder 39)
- We Will Decide the Fate of Croatia Ourselves, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Where Do the Crayfish Winter?, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Where to Go, Virumaa!?, 1989 (Map-folder 40)
- Will the Swans Return?, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Wir Sind Das Volk! - We Are The People, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Wolf Vostell, 9 November 1989, Berlin, 1990 (Map-folder 41)
- Yeltsin, Boris Nikolaevich, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Yeltsin, Boris Nikolaevich, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Yeltsin, Boris Nikolaevich - Candidate for the People's Deputy of the USSR, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Yeltsin Campaign Poster, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- You Are Leaving the American Sector, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)